Chekhov says in one of his plays describing one man,
契诃夫的剧本里描述过一个人
“He was a simple man. A stupid man.”
“他是个简单的人，一个愚蠢的人。”
[Simple-Hearted or Simpleton]
是单纯还是蠢
So, there’s simple-hearted and simpleton.
有些人是单纯简朴，有些人单单是蠢
So someone who is interested to advance spiritually,
所以有意在灵性上进步的人
we’re told,
经典里说
hṛdayenabhyanujñāto yo dharmas taṁ nibhodhata [Ms: 2.01]
hṛdayenabhyanujñāto yo dharmas taṁ nibhodhata (Ms: 2.01梵文诗节)
they will factor in that,
他们知道，
“I have a strong tendency towards self-deception;
“我经常性地会自我欺骗，
I can see it in my life, in my circumstances.
这总在我人生中发生
So, knowing that I have a tendency to do that,
明白我有这种习性，
let this not be another example of that—
所以我希望在灵性道路上
my making spiritual connections.”
能够避开这种自欺欺人。”
So then we have to look into tradition, lineage, etc.
所以我们必须检查灵性传承的体系。
Gandhi, when the British were there,
在英国殖民时期，英雄甘地
he realised that khādī (the cloth made by the charkha
他意识到khādī这种衣服
and from the cotton, and the weavers, by hand),
是用手纺机人工手织出的
every aspect of it is hand;
每一步都是手工出品的
he thought, “This is good for India.
他想，“这对印度有益
It’s good for the people in the villages;
对村里纺织的村民也有好处
it’s good for the country.
对国家很好。
So if you believe in India, just buy khādī;
如果你相信印度，就买khādī;
don’t buy the factory mill cloth of the British.”
不要买英国工厂制造的衣服。”
So a movement started growing.
所以就此开始了纺织运动
But then—the British are very clever;
但是英国人很聪明
in their factory they learned how to produce cloth
他们学会了让工厂仿造看似是khādī手工出品的衣服
that looks like khādī. So they started selling it.
并开始销售
So this led him to establish the Khādī Saṅgha.
因此，甘地便成立了Khādī Saṅgha
It’s still there in Kolkata, and other places you can find.
时至今日，在印度加尔各答等地方依然可以看到这个协会
—[Swāmī Avadhūt] “I bought some stuff there.” —“Yes.”
—[Swāmī Avadhūt] “我在那还买过东西.” —“是的.”
So the Khādī Saṅgha … And what he was saying,
他针对Khādī Saṅgha说
“We’re starting an association, us, who really know
“我们这个协会真正知道
what khādī is in the pure state,
纯粹的khādī手工衣服是怎样的。
it will have our stamp and our seal on it.
真正的布料，我们会打上协会标志，
If it does not have the stamp and seal of the Khādī Saṅgha,
如果没有Khādī Saṅgha的标志，
it’s counterfeit, it’s not the real thing.”
那这布料是假冒的，不是真的。”
So, in something as serious as spiritual culture,
所以，面对更谨慎认真的灵性文化
someone’s going to have to invest some time,
你需要投入时间精力
some energy, do some research,
去调查研究下那个灵性传承的背景
but ultimately, what Manu says, and what I quoted,
但最终，我引用玛努（人类始姐）的话，
yo dharmas taṁ nibho …
yo dharmas taṁ nibho …
hṛdayenabhyanujñāto yo dharmas taṁ nibhodhata— [Ms: 2.01]
（梵文诗节）
ultimately it’s an affair of the heart.
最终这由你的心决定
And now we’re back to that point:
我们回到刚刚说的话题：
simple-hearted or simpleton?
是心思简单还是愚蠢？
Self-deceiver or sincere, earnest hankering for the truth?
是自欺还是诚挚地渴求真理？
So Śrīla Guru Mahārāj has an aphorism
Śrīla Guru Mahārāj有一句格言
that actually applies to everything,
适用于所有情形
including all the varieties of theistic culture
包括你知道的各种
that you could possibly conceive.
神本文化
Everything is included within this one sūtra-like expression
所有都含括在这一句经典表达里
in which he says,
他说，
“According to the inner sincere hankering of your heart
“根据你内心的真挚渴求
you will come in connection with a particular level
你会找到对应层次的神性文化
of theistic conception and subsequent association—
并进一步进行联谊和交流。
that’s guaranteed.” So then what we’re left with is,
这是确保的”。 所以剩下的就是
“Oh! Then as long as I’m sincere, everything will be all-right.
“哦，只要我真诚，一切会好好的
As long as I’m sincere, I’ll make the right choice.
只要我真诚，就会做出正确的选择。
ultimately I’ll get there.”
只要我真诚，最终我会到达彼岸。”
And that’s again grounded in the Gīta,
《博伽梵歌》里也有确认
where Kṛṣṇa tells Arjuna,
奎师那告诉阿尔诸那
na hi kalyāṇa-kṛt kaśchid durgatiṁ tāta gachchhati [Bg: 6.40]
（梵文诗歌）
which Guru Mahārāj renders sometimes as
Guru Mahārāj有时解释说
“The sincere will be victorious”
“真诚将所向无敌”
or “Sincerity is invincible.”
“真诚是不可战胜的”